CECELIA FOWLER

SOFTWARE ENGINEER

203-598-6307

dev@ceceliafowler.com



ceceliafowler.com



www.linkedin.com/in/ceceliafowler



https://github.com/cecelia001

PROFILE

Full Stack Developer with graduate level training in education and 4+ years managerial experience. Practical experience building applications from start to finish, including working with databases and APIs, performing unit testing, and implementing front-end frameworks. Lifelong learner with a diverse range of certifications and a strong desire to expand my skills.

EDUCATION

Full Stack Bootcamp Certificate 2022

CodeOp | Barcelona, Spain

2015

University of Bridgeport | Bridgeport, CT

Bachelor of Science | Education

Master of Science | Education

2013

Western CT State University | Danbury, CT

TECHNICAL SKILLS

JavaScript Node.js

React/Vue Express

HTML/CSS MySQL

Bootstrap TDD/JEST

Advanced Git Postman

EXPERIENCE

Full Stack Developer Sept 2022 - Dec 2022

CodeOp | Barcelona, Spain

Three months of intensive full time bootcamp covering full stack technologies: JavaScript ES6+, React, ReactContext, API, Node.js, Express and MySQL, and more. Built 3 full stack projects.

Head of Youth Services

Feb 2018 - Sept 2022

Howard Whittemore & Terryville Library

Supervised and trained staff of 9 and 15 volunteers. Oversaw short and long term budgets of \$15k. Fostered 6 new partnerships within the community. Boosted attendance of programs by 35%.

Financial Consultant

Jan 2016 - Feb 2018

AXA Advisors

Advised a total of \$6 AUM in retirement accounts. Generated 15+ leads weekly. Communicated regularly with over 130 clients, using Salesforce. Maintained all related licensing, compliance, and training.

Classroom Teacher

Aug 2013 - Jan 2016

Regional District 16

Developed instruction to meet diverse learning needs. Monitored student performance and prepared weekly reports to present at team meetings. Increased reading and math scores by 30%.

PROJECTS

Roadtrip Social Planner

December 2022

Built with: JavaScript, React, Node.js, **Bootstrap**

Worked with an international team to create a full stack app with 3rd party API integration and authorization.

Productivity Tracker

November 2022

Built with: JSON Web Token, Bcrypt, JavaScript, React, MySQL, Chakra UI

Inherited legacy code to implement authentication and authorization, allowing for user registration and login.

Monthly Expense Analysis

October 2022

Built with: JavaScript, React, Bootstrap, Express, Node.js, MySQL, REST APIs

Full stack app designed to monitor monthly expenses and establish personalized budgets for different categories.